https://redochre.org.uk/privacy-policy/

Contact Us
Privacy Policy
Magic
Our mission is to improve the performance of individuals, organisations and businesses that deliver social change
Privacy Policy
Our promise to you as Red Ochre is that we will only use your data to help us provide the right experience for you as a customer
We’ll protect your data as if it’s our own
We’ll always respect your choices on what we do with your data and how we contact you
We’ll only keep it as long as necessary
Red Ochre is committed to respecting your privacy and the privacy of every visitor to our web site and all of our customers.
The information we collect about you will be used to fulfil the required services and enable us to improve how, as an organisation, we deal with you.
Should you have a question about the data we store, our contact details are:
020-7250-8306
The information that we collect about you will only be used lawfully (in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and the General Data Protection Regulation 2018). All data is retained exclusively within the United Kingdom, or transferred only to ‘third countries’ where ‘adequacy of protection’ or specific certification as defined by The GDPR has been confirmed.
This information will not be disclosed to anyone outside Red Ochre or its associated companies, partners, and other companies with which Red Ochre has arranged services for your benefit.
We expect the information we hold to be accurate and up to date. You have the right as an individual to find out what information we hold about you and make changes if necessary; you also have the right, assuming we are not obligated by law to refuse, to ask us to stop using the information.  To have your information removed or rectified, please contact robert@redochre.org.uk.
The type of information that we will collect on you, and you voluntarily provide to us includes:
Your name
Organisation and position
Address
Telephone number(s)
Email address
Survey responses, such as training courses you are interested in
Information for system logs such as IP addresses and other communication data
We may, in further dealings with you, extend this information to include your address, purchases, services used, and subscriptions, records of conversations and agreements and payment transactions.
You are under no statutory or contractual requirement or obligation to provide us with your personal information; however we require at least the information above in order for us to deal with you as a potential customer in an efficient and effective manner.
We need to maintain your information for a certain period to provide customer support, purchase history, prevention of fraud and analytics information.
The legal basis for processing your data is based on either:
Your specific consent for general information and communication that we have requested at the time of sign up, or that you explicitly volunteered
For performance of a contract if you are a client of Red Ochre
We will not store, process or transfer your data outside the parties detailed above unless we have an appropriate lawful reason to do so.
Unless we are precluded from doing so by law, you have the right to remove your consent at any time via the unsubscribe link included on all emails we send, or by contacting us and requesting that processing of your details be restricted or deleted.
Unless otherwise required by law, your data will be stored for a period of 2 years after our last contact with you at which point it will be deleted.
PROTECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
Red Ochre takes precautions, including administrative, technical, and physical measures, to safeguard your Data against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.
Red Ochre uses industry-standard efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of Data, including encryption, firewalls and SSL (Secure Sockets Layer). We have implemented reasonable administrative, technical, and physical security controls to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of your Data.
COOKIES
This site uses cookies – these are small text files that are placed on your device to help this website to provide a better user experience. In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences, store information for things like shopping carts, and provide anonymised tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics. As a rule, cookies will make your browsing experience better. However, you may prefer to disable cookies on this site and on others. The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser. We suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at the About Cookies website which offers guidance for all modern browsers.
GOOGLE ANALYTICS
This website sets “first party” cookies through its use of Google Analytics. We use Google Analytics to provide us with non-personal site analytics, which in turn help us improve this website. Google Analytics tracking uses cookies in order to provide meaningful reports about web site visitors’ but they do not collect personal data about you. Google Analytics sets or updates cookies only to collect data required for the reports. Additionally, Google Analytics only uses first-party cookies. This means that all cookies set by Google Analytics cannot be altered or retrieved by any service on any domain other than www.redochre.org.uk.  Further detailed information on Google Analytics cookies can be found here.
If you have a concern about how we handle your data, or you would like to lodge a complaint, you may do so by contacting The Information Commissioners Office.
Red Ochre Newsletter
First Name
Surname
Organisation
Email
Contact us © 2013-20 Red Ochre
CAN Mezzanine
49 - 51 East Road
